Luis Sánchez

Senior Software Engineer

Profile

Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 8+ years of experience successful completing simultaneous projects. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. Resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. Decisive leader and reliable team builder with results-focused and driven approach.

Employment History

Software Engineer (Sr) at In Motion, Santiago, Chile

April 2012 - Present

- Extensive use of .NET 4.7, C#, MVC, Entity Framework 6 and Core, ASP.NET Identity, Identity Server, Web API.
- Lead small projects from start to finish with at least two (2) developers in the team using agile methodologies.
- Use of Microservices architecture.
- ASP.NET Web APIs | Rest API's.
- API V3 Google Maps.
- Use of CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap and JavaScript to improve legacy sites.
- Creation of Docker images using Azure DevOps with CI and CD.
- TDD, Unit tests with xunit and FluentAssertions.
- WWF, WPF and WCF.
- New projects are starting with .Net Core.
- Support technical interviews for software developer positions in the company.

Jr. Information Technology Analyst at Atento, Caracas, Venezuela

June 2010 — March 2012

- Design of Web Applications using MVC3 Razor, CCS3 for multiple clients with the latest technologies of the moment.
- Creation of ETLs with SQL Server 2008 R2 and Visual Studio 2008 (SSIS).
- Use of Google Maps API v3.
- Interaction with multiple clients: Nestlé, Telefonica, BBVA Provincial.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Informatics Engineering, Universidad Católica Andrés Bello, Caracas, Venezuela

October 2009 — September 2003

High School Diploma, U.E. Santa Elena, Caracas, Venezuela

September 1998 — July 2003

Courses

ScrumManager, Expert level, ScrumManager.org

June 2015 — June 2015

TS: Microsoft .NET Framework - Application Development Foundation. Microsoft License 9023486, Microsoft

March 2012 — March 2012

Details

Simón Bolívar 2580, Santiago, 7750000, Chile, +56 9 6432 9625 luis.sanchezm86@gmail.com

Links

Twitter

LinkedIn

Stackoverflow

GitHub

Experimental website

Skills

.NET C#, EF, Web API, MVC

Team Work

ASP.NET Identity, Identity

Server

Microservices architecture

CSS3, HTML, JavaScript

PL/SQL and T-SQL

Xamarin

Google API and GCP

Azure platform

Languages

Spanish

English

Hobbies

Cooking, Running, Tennis, Bicycling, PC gaming.